Guide to the David Starr Jordan Papers SC0058
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Biographical Material, Series VIII-A
  - Miscellaneous biographical material, 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical material, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical material, 1872-1910 (Box 1, Folder 3a)
  - Biographical material, 1872-1910 (Box 1, Folder 3b)
  - Biographical material, 1911-1912 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Biographical material, 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Biographical material, 1916-1923 (Box 2, Folder 6a)
  - Biographical material, 1916-1923 (Box 2, Folder 6b)
  - Biographical material, 1924-1928 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Biographical material, 1929 (Box 3A, Folder 8)
  - Biographical material, 1930 (Box 3A, Folder 9)
  - Biographical material, 1931, January-October (Box 3A, Folder 10a)
  - Biographical material, 1931, January-October (Box 3B, Folder 10b)
  - Biographical material, 1931, October-December (Box 3B, Folder 11a)
  - Biographical material, 1931, October-December (Box 3B, Folder 11b)
  - Biographical material, 1932-1933 (Box 3B, Folder 12)
  - Biographical material, 1934-1949 (Box 4, Folder 13a)
  - Biographical material, 1934-1949 (Box 4, Folder 13b)
  - Biographical material, 1950-1963 (Box 4, Folder 14a)
  - Biographical material, 1950-1963 (Box 4, Folder 14b)
  - Biographical material, 1964- (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Biographical material, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Genealogical Material, Series VIII-B
  Historical and biographical material on the Jordan family, genealogical research notes and charts, material on immediate family and contemporary relatives. Excerpts from the unpublished autobiography of Edith Jordan Gardner. Copies were made through the courtesy of Mrs. Ruth Jordan Gates, granddaughter of Dr. Jordan and owner of the original.
  - General material (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Geneological material, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Geneological material (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Geneological material, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Photographs, Series IX
  The photographs from this series have been removed from the collection and are now part of the General Photograph Collection.
- Reference File, Series X
  Clippings on a variety of subjects, but not David Starr Jordan. Probably collected as a reference file.
  - Printed reference material: Frank Miller and Mission Inn (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Printed reference material (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Printed reference material (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Printed reference material (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Printed reference material (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Printed reference material: Abraham Lincoln Foundation, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Printed reference material (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Printed reference material (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Printed reference material (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Printed reference material (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Printed reference material (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Printed reference material (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Printed reference material (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Personal reference notes (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Personal reference notes (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Personal reference notes (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Printed reference material (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Provenance of microfilm project (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Provenance of microfilm project (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Provenance of microfilm project (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous, Series XI
  Calling cards, membership cards, commissions, wedding invitations, programs, honorary degrees and similar matter.
  - Invitations and certificates (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Invitations and certificates (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Invitations and certificates (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Invitations and certificates (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Invitations and certificates (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Invitations and clippings (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Personal souvenirs (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Autograph book from Japanese alumni (Box 6)
  - Jordan's medals (Box 7)
  - Jordan Manuscript (Box 8)
  - Jordan family Bible (in German) with family data and Jordan's notation of his wife Susan's last words (Volume Vol)
  - Certificate: Comité Américain Pour Les Régions Dévastées (American Committee for Devastated France). Awarded to Madame Davide Starr Jordan., 1916-1923; 9.1 (Box 9)
  - Genealogy of The Fittest by Sarah Louise Kimball for the book YOUR FAMILY TREE by Kimball and Jordan (original), 9.2 (Box 9)
  - Genealogy of The Fittest by Sarah Louise Kimball for the book YOUR FAMILY TREE by Kimball and Jordan (silverprint copy), 9.3 (Box 9)
- Printed Works, Series XII
  Numbers refer to those used in Alice N. Hays, David Starr Jordan: A Bibliography of His Writings 1871-1931.
  - Hays #24=Ulrich Von Hutten, 1886 (Box 1A, Item 1.1)
  - Printed works - articles and reprints, 1-49 (Box 1A, Folder 1.2)
  - Printed works, 50-99 (Box 1A, Folder 2)
  - Printed works, 100-200 (Box 1A, Folder 3)
  - Printed works, 201-300 (Box 1B, Folder 4)
  - Printed works, 301-349 (Box 1B, Folder 5)
  - Printed works, 350-399 (Box 1B, Folder 6)
  - Printed works, 400-498 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Printed works, 504-626 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Printed works, 627-670 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Printed works, 671 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Printed works, 674-694 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Printed works, 700-799 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Printed works, 800-899 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Printed works, 900-1000 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Printed works, 1001-1172 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Printed works, 1220-1276 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Printed works, 1277-1299 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Printed works, 1300-1351 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Printed works, 1352-1371 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Printed works, F1-F200 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Printed works, F201-F299 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Printed works, F300-F465 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Printed works, F466-F564 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Printed works, F565-F606 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Printed works, F607-F639 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Synopsis of the fishes of North America. By David S. Jordan and Charles H. Gilbert., 1882; 1 volume(s) (Box 7)
  - The fossil fishes of California, with supplementary notes on other species of extinct fishes, 1907 Apr (Box 8)
  - The mountaineer (vol. 16), 1923 Dec 15 (Box 8)
  - An appeal for cooperation toward lasting peace, undated (Box 8)
  - A quarter century of Stanford University, 1916 Jul 1 (Box 8)
  - Adolph Sutro's letter to the Regents of the University of California, 1895 Sep 5 (Box 8)
  - The keys to success...are found in attending the alumni meetings, 1931 Oct 8-10 (Box 8)
  - More Elbow Room, 1923 Apr (Box 8)
  - Stanford Illustrated Review, 1932 Feb (Box 8)
  - Darwinism, 1888 (Box 8)
  - Alumni trustee, 1888 Jun (Box 8)
  - A sage in science, 1899 Apr 14 (Box 8)
  - Ce que l'Amerique peut enseigner a l'Europe, 1913 (Box 8)
  - War business and insurance, 1915 Nov (Box 8)
  - The future of Alsace-Lorraine, 1918 Jul (Box 8)
  - A clean college life, 1898 Jan 8 (Box 8)
  - Address on religion, 1897 Apr 26 (Box 8)
  - Out of door Americans, 1897 Apr 26 (Box 8)
  - The Balkan tragedy, 1918 Oct (Box 8)
  - Why eastern students come to Stanford University, 1897 May 2 (Box 8)
  - A castle in Spain, 1894 Dec 6 (Box 8)
  - President Jordan on the high school course, 1908 Mar (Box 8)
  - University life in the Antipodes, undated (Box 8)
  - The colors of letters, undated (Box 8)
  - Scientific temperance, undated (Box 8)
  - The sympsychograph: a study in impressionist physics, undated (Box 8)
  - Old rattler and the king snake, undated (Box 8)
  - Is Russia to control all of Asia?, undated (Box 8)
  - The sequel in Japan, undated (Box 8)
  - Recent physiology, undated (Box 8)
  - In the little brook, undated (Box 8)
  - Rescue work in history, undated (Box 8)
  - In search of the truth, undated (Box 8)
  - Imperial democracy, undated (Box 8)
  - Science and non-science, 1897 May 6 (Box 8)
  - Imperial democracy, 1898 Dec (Box 8)
  - Putting away childish things, 1898 Jan 6 (Box 8)
  - The silent city of the Muir Glacier, 1898 Jan 6 (Box 8)
  - The racial geography of europe, 1887 (Box 8)
  - The League of Nations, undated (Box 8)
  - An appeal for cooperation towards lasting peace, 1916 Mar 21 (Box 8)
  - International aspects of certain biological problems of the North Pacific, undated (Box 8)
  - Biological effects of race movements, undated (Box 8)
  - Military training in American high schools, undated (Box 8)
  - Temperance and society, 1911 Jul (Box 8)
  - On a forgotten genus of sharks described Nardo, 1917 Aug (Box 8)
  - To Barbara, undated (Box 8)
  - Reprints and notes (Box 9)
- Publications (Volumes), Series XIII
  - 47a-94 (Box 1)
  - 97-151, 212-238, 339 (Box 2)
  - 181 (Box 3)
  - 280-483 (Box 4)
  - 793-1164 (Box 5)
  - 604-793 (Box 6)
- Additional Material (Correspondence), Accession ARCH.1988-058, ARCH.1988-125
  - Drake University 25th Anniversary Celebration invitation to DS Jordan, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jordan, D.S. to Mrs. Stinson, 1927 Feb 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional Material, circa 1924-1931; Accession ARCH-2004-208
  - Letter to Mrs. Beach Thompson, 1927 Jan 23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Carl H. Eigenmann thank ing him; "What's My Name" biography of Jordan by Mrs. Carl H. Eigenmann, 1924 Dec 30, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Publications by Jordan (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2018-114
  - DSJ to Paul A. Gilmore, 1892 Jan 23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - DSJ to O. L. Elliott, 1913 Jan 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)